<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.0.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-04-27T11:51:46+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Your awesome title</title><subtitle>Write an awesome description for your new site here. You can edit this line in _config.yml. It will appear in your document head meta (for Google search results) and in your feed.xml site description.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Reborn</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2019/08/17/Reborn.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Reborn" /><published>2019-08-17T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2019-08-17T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2019/08/17/Reborn</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2019/08/17/Reborn.html">&lt;h1 id=&quot;reborn&quot;&gt;Reborn?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alright, so we are back from where we start. And we always start from Square one. I am fed up of this, but I don’t think I have anything else to do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am extremely irrated but that’s what it is. I can’t do anything about it. +&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I can do is to make a plan again. Write something and then hope I stick with it long enough.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;OK, let’s start with what’s the problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am not in a happy state and I want to come out of it. My family is making me feel like an idiot. I am fed up of this constant nuisance at home but more than that I am fedup with this escapasim habit of mine. I want to come out of it. How will I come out I don’t know.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s painful even to talk about it. OK so what do you want?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I just want out of this discomfort, but how will you come out of the discomfort if you are not ready to face it bro. Anyways, so all we can agree is that the only way out of this rut is to work. To hustle, to take action. And to take important actions first.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s a skill, it’s a habit and it must be developed. Only then will I be able to do something about it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, let’s talk about what we can do. And we can stop doing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First and foremost the don’ts. And I must say that this is not the end. This will require long hours of practice and the will to go through discomfort. And let me also admit that if I am not willing to hustle, to work hard, then I will remain like this forever. I will not be able to give my wife any happiness and neither my child.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don’t want that . And I will work hard that it doesn’t happen. Look brother, I know it’s hard but remember that if you don’t even try it out now , then you are going to regret it later.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what are the most important problems plaguing me right now. First is that I don’t have a clear vision of what I want to do . There are  multiple things to be done but I am not making initiative in any of it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can try applying for Autralian Visa. I can work on getting SAP certified and then look for switching jobs. Or I must buy a property. At least one of these 3 I must do within this year, otherwise I will be screwed. And I don’t want that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But let’s start with the basics. What’s the problem I am facing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First and foremost these internet and devices. They have screwed up my life. I must give this up and then only can I think of doing something else.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;OK so what are the things I am willing to ban from today onwards until at least start of 2020?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Netflix and others like Youtube and Prime Videos.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;All forms of social media including news.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;iPad except during Ludo.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What’s allowed?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;TV News&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Books&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Podcasts&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Music&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Whatsapp on Laptop&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And what I must do on a daily basis?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Exercise at least half an hour which may be gym or bodyweight or jogging.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Meditation for 5 mins at least.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Learning something for at least an hour daily after office hours.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Spending 1 hour with family and catching up on friend.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Writing daily at least 500 words.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If I can do all this on a daily basis, I think I can get into a better frame of mind. But this must all start by getting up early in the morning. By 7 am at least. Once, I start getting up at 7 am daily, I think I will be able to make my life much better. I will get time to do all that I have envisioned. Anyways, let’s see . Let’s see how it will go. God Help me.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Reborn?</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Git</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2019/03/16/git.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Git" /><published>2019-03-16T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2019-03-16T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2019/03/16/git</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2019/03/16/git.html">&lt;p&gt;OK so today I learnt a bit about Git and Github.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While I have learned them earlier before too and know the basics, but since I don’t practise as much as I keep on forgetting it which isn’t good. This is my way to keep everything together and learn the basics and also have a reference material to look into in the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over a period of time, I hope I develop a style of keeping stuff together in a certain way . However, one problem that I see in this way of blogging is how to inser the images at the appropriate place. But let’s figure it out over a period of time. Right now the main thing would be get a hang of it, practice and develop a habit. Let’s see how it goes….&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>ravs</name></author><summary type="html">OK so today I learnt a bit about Git and Github.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Jekyll</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2019/03/15/jekyll.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Jekyll" /><published>2019-03-15T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2019-03-15T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2019/03/15/jekyll</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2019/03/15/jekyll.html">&lt;p&gt;OK so this is my first post on a blog made through &lt;strong&gt;Jekyll&lt;/strong&gt; ( from &lt;del&gt;Microsoft&lt;/del&gt; the makers of Github!). And in true meta style I am writing it here on &lt;em&gt;Jekyll&lt;/em&gt; itself. It’s using quite a lot of technologies to bring together a blog.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HTML/CSS/JS&lt;/strong&gt; are there of course.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Plus we have got Markdown for writing blogs.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Liquid for structuring the content.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Yaml format for defining variables.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;And in general a special way to structure the site itself.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name>ravs</name></author><summary type="html">OK so this is my first post on a blog made through Jekyll ( from Microsoft the makers of Github!). And in true meta style I am writing it here on Jekyll itself. It’s using quite a lot of technologies to bring together a blog.</summary></entry></feed>